HARSHDEEP SINGH

https://harshdeeply.netlify.app/

Highlights

- ★ A recent graduate from BCIT School of Computing and Academic Studies
- ★ Highly ambitious and passionate self-learner
- ★ Project experience in JavaScript, React, and React Native

Technical Skills

Languages	Tools	Libraries/Frameworks	SQA	uı/ux
HTML/CSS	Slack	React/Angular	Automated testing	Wireframing
JavaScript/TypeScript	Trello/Jira	React Native/Ionic	Writing test cases	Prototyping
Python	Git	Node.js	Documenting reports	Usability Testing

Project Experience

★ Portfolio Website

- Created a static site using React and Gatsby and deployed on Netlify
- Integrated icons and graphics from third party libraries such as font awesome and feather icons into React components
- Utilized third party forms to create 'contact' page
- Set up custom CI/CD pipelines to automatically deploy when source code is updated

★ React Native Game (Course Project)

March 2020 - April 2020

- Created 2048 game in react native
- o Integrated Google authentication API to allow users to sign in
- Used 'react native animatable' to add animations

★ ReactJS calculator (Personal Project)

October 2020 - November 2020

- Wire-framed calculator UI grid using Figma
- Animated the interface of the calculator to enhance user experience

Work Experience

★ Zeniox, *Montréal, QB*

May 2020 - September 2020

Technical Support Agent (Full Time, remote)

- Rapidly devised solutions to technical problems/difficulties faced by non technical end users via telephone, email, and chat
- Gained experience communicating with end users of various backgrounds
- Provide daily support to users of various computer systems including answering questions, analyzing problems, and quickly forming solutions to return systems to proper operation

★ Xorosoft Inc, Burnaby, BC

May 2019 - April 2020

Junior Software Developer (Technical Intern)

- Identified customer needs and helped customers use specific features of an ERP software (SaaS)
- Participated in pair-programming to work on bug fixes
- Engaged with intermediate/senior developers to learn the codebase and development environment

Education

★ British Columbia Institute of Technology

January 2019 - December 2020

Computer Information Technology (Post Secondary Diploma)

- Full-Stack Web Development
- UI/UX Designing
- Database Administration
- Algorithms and Data Structures
- Mobile Application Development

Hackathons

★ NASA Space Apps COVID-19 Challenge

May 2020

 Worked in a team of 6 on hacking for the COVID-19 pandemic where we used the NASA satellite data to plot the green land (parks in our case) and based on algorithms, the program outputs a "risk-rating" number that marks the risk percentage for different parks

★ Justice Hack November 2019

 Worked in a team of 5 on extracting data using python from public judicial sources to accumulate it and present the statistics.

★ Vanhacks October 2019

- Created an offline accessible progressive web app using react and gatsby for linkvan.ca, an initiative to make food, shelter and other resources more available to the homeless population of Vancouver
- Learnt about service-workers and processing json data in React